

Robotics and Computer Vision Lab., Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

□ (+82) 10-9509-3491 | 🗷 jjang9hsm@kaist.ac.kr | 🏕 soonminhwang.github.io | 🖸 soonminhwang | 🛅 smhwang

# Summary\_

I am a Ph.D student advised by Prof. In So Kweon in EE department, KAIST. I worked as a fulltime research intern in computer vision group at Qualcomm Research Austria. My research interest are robust visual perception technologies for autonomous driving in day and night. I have broad interests about various computer vision algorithm for autonomous driving, e.g. object detection, segmentation, depth estimation, etc. I have been pursuing various computer vision algorithms to turn ultimate AI-powered sensors into reality.

## **Education**

### KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, S.Korea

Ph.D. STUDENT

Mar. 2014 - present

- · Topic: Object detection, Deep learning, Sensor fusion
- Advisor: Prof. In So Kweon

### KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, S.Korea Feb. 2012 - Feb. 2014

MS

• Thesis: A Hierarchical Classifier Model based on Deformable Part Models and Random Forest for Robust Pedestrian Detection

· Advisor: Prof. In So Kweon

**Hanyang University** Seoul, S.Korea

B.S. Mar. 2007 - Feb. 2012

· Recognize and Play a Music Score on Android Smartphone

# Research Interests

### Computer vision for self-driving cars

- Object detection (e.g. pedestrians, cars) / Semantic segmentation
- Image enhancement / 3D scene understanding

### Deep learning for computer vision

- Dynamic neural network
- Adversarial machine learning for computer vision

#### **Sensor fusion**

- RGB camera + Thermal camera (Long wavelength IR)
- RGB camera + 3D LiDAR

# Work experience\_

### **Full-time Research Intern**

Vienna, Austria

COMPUTER VISION GROUP, OUALCOMM RESEARCH

Jul. 2016 - Nov. 2016

· Lane marker detection using deep neural network

# **Full-time Intern**

Hanyang Univ., Seoul, S.Korea

MIXED REALITY LAB. (PROF. JONG-IL PARK)

Nov. 2010 - Feb. 2011

• Development of view morphing system for relics

# **Projects**

# **Automatic Emergency Braking for Pedestrian Protection**

MINISTRY OF TRADE, INDUSTRY AND ENERGY OF KOREA (MOTIE)

Jun. 2013 - PRESENT

Mar 2012 - Feb 2017

• Accurate pedestrian detection using multiple sensor fusion

### Personal Plug and Play DigiCar (P3 DigiCar)

NATIONAL RESEARCH FOUNDATION OF KOREA

· Robust pedestrian detection using monocular camera

### **DATMO: Detection and Tracking Moving Object using 3D LiDAR**

LIG-Nexi Co. Ltd, S.Korea *Apr. 2015 - Nov. 2015* 

· On-road object detection and tracking (pedestrian, car) using 3D-LiDAR

· Camera & 3D LiDAR fusion

### Monocular Vision based Natural Feature Extraction for Cognitive Model

MINISTRY OF KNOWLEDGE ECONOMY OF KOREA Sep. 2012 - Dec. 2013

• Porting developed natural feature algorithm to embedded system

# Publications\_

### **KAIST Multispectral Recognition Dataset in Day and Night**

IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON INTELLIGENT TRANSPORTATION SYSTEMS (TITS)

Yukyung Choi, Namil Kim, Soonmin Hwang, Kibaek Park, Jae Shin Yoon, Kyunghwan An, In So Kweon

StairNet: Top-Down Semantic Aggregation for Accurate One Shot Detection

IEEE WINTER CONF. ON APPLICATIONS OF COMPUTER VISION (WACV)

Sanghyun Woo, **Soonmin Hwang**, In So Kweon

Multispectral Transfer Network: Unsupervised Depth Estimation for All-day Vision

THE THIRTY-SECOND AAAI CONFERENCE ON ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE (AAAI)

Namil Kim\*, Yukyung Choi\*, **Soonmin Hwang**, In So Kweon

Thermal Image Enhancement using Convolutional Neural Network

THE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE OF INTELLIGENT ROBOTS AND SYSTEMS (IROS)

Namil Kim\*, Yukyung Choi\*, **Soonmin Hwang\***, In So Kweon

Fast Multiple Objects Detection and Tracking Fusing Color Camera and 3D LIDAR for

**Intelligent Vehicles** 

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON UBIQUITOUS ROBOTS AND AMBIENT INTELLIGENCE (URAI)

Soonmin Hwang\*, Namil Kim\*, Yukyung Choi, Seokju Lee, In So Kweon

Thermal-Infrared based Drivable Region Detection

IEEE INTELLIGENT VEHICLES SYMPOSIUM (IV)

Jae Shin Yoon, Kibaek Park, **Soonmin Hwang**, Namil Kim, Yukyung Choi, In So Kweon

**Low-Cost Synchronization for Multispectral Cameras** 

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON UBIQUITOUS ROBOTS AND AMBIENT INTELLIGENCE (URAI)

Soonmin Hwang, Yukyung Choi, Namil Kim, Kibaek Park, Jae Shin Yoon, In So Kweon

**Geometrical Calibration of Multispectral Calibration** 

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON UBIQUITOUS ROBOTS AND AMBIENT INTELLIGENCE (URAI)

Namil Kim, Yukyung Choi, **Soonmin Hwang**, Kibaek Park, Jae Shin Yoon, In So Kweon

**ARTRIEVAL: Painting Retrieval Without Expert Knowledge** 

IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON IMAGE PROCESSING (ICIP)

Namil Kim, Yukyung Choi, **Soonmin Hwang**, In So Kweon

All-Day Visual Place Recognition: Benchmark Dataset and Baselines

IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER VISION AND PATTERN RECOGNITION WORKSHOPS (CVPRW-VPRICE)

Yukyung Choi, Namil Kim, Kibaek Park, **Soonmin Hwang**, Jae Shin Yoon, In So Kweon

Multispectral Pedestrian Detection: Benchmark Dataset and Baselines

IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER VISION AND PATTERN RECOGNITION (CVPR)

Soonmin Hwang, Jaesik Park, Namil Kim, Yukyung Choi, In So Kweon

Mar. 2018

2018

Lake Tahoe, USA

New Orleans, USA

Feb. 2018

Daejeon, S.Korea

Oct. 2016

Xian, China

Aug. 2016

Gothenburg, Sweden

....

Goyang, S.Korea

Oct. 2015

Goyang, S.Korea

y arrig, or torea

Oct. 2015

Québec, Canada

2015

Boston, USA

Jun. 2015

Boston, USA

Jun. 2015

### A Two Phase Approach for Pedestrian Detection

ASIAN CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER VISION WORKSHOPS (ACCV WORKSHOPS)

Singapore, Singapore

Nov. 2014

**Soonmin Hwang**, Tae-hyun Oh, In So Kweon

## **Evaluation of Vocabulary Trees for Localization in Robot Applications**

Gwangju, S.Korea

Oct. 2013

International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS) **Soonmin Hwang**, Chaehoon Park, Yukyung Choi, Donggeun Yoo, In So Kweon

# Honors & Awards \_\_

2018	<b>Encouragement prize</b>	The 24th HumanTech Paper Award, Samsung Electronics Co. Ltd, (\$2,000, acceptance rate 6.5%)
2017	Gold prize	The 23th HumanTech Paper Award, Samsung Electronics Co. Ltd, (\$10,000, acceptance rate 0.7%)
2016	1st Place	NVidia Deep Learning Contest, NVidia Korea
2016	Bronze prize	Korea Invention Patent Exhibition (KINPEX)

# Skills\_

**Languages** Python, MATLAB, C/C++

**Libraries** PyTorch, Caffe, OpenCV, QT, PCL, MFC, and others